|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| [](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/) | Welcome to the most active **[Linux Forum](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b)** on the web. |

|     |
| --- |

|     |     |     |     |     |     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| [](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/privacy.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) **Privacy Policy** |     |     |

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| User Name |     | Remember Me? |     |
| Password |     |     |

|     |
| --- |
| Notices |
| Welcome to **LinuxQuestions.org**, a friendly and active Linux Community.  <br>  <br>You are currently viewing LQ as a guest. By joining our community you will have the ability to post topics, receive our newsletter, use the advanced search, subscribe to threads and access many other special features. Registration is quick, simple and absolutely free. [**Join our community**](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/register.php) today!  <br>  <br>**Note that registered members see fewer ads, and ContentLink is completely disabled once you log in.**  <br>  <br>Are you new to LinuxQuestions.org? Visit the following links:  <br>[Site Howto](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/answers/LinuxQuestions_org/How_to_Use_LinuxQuestions_org?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) \| [Site FAQ](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/faq.php) \| [Sitemap](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/sitemap.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) \| [Register Now](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/register.php)  <br>  <br>If you have any problems with the registration process or your account login, please [contact us](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/sendmessage.php). If you need to reset your password, [click here](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/login.php?do=lostpw).  <br>  <br>**Having a problem logging in? Please visit [this page](https://www.linuxquestions.org/removecookies.php) to clear all LQ-related cookies.**<br><br>  <br>Get a [virtual cloud desktop](https://www.shells.com/l/en-US/linux-questions-org-exclusive?_a=RCzIFy) with the Linux distro that you want in less than five minutes with Shells! With over 10 pre-installed distros to choose from, the worry-free installation life is here! Whether you are a digital nomad or just looking for flexibility, Shells can put your Linux machine on the device that you want to use.  <br>  <br>Exclusive for LQ members, get up to 45% off per month. [Click here](https://www.shells.com/l/en-US/linux-questions-org-exclusive?_a=RCzIFy) for more info. |

|     |
| --- |
| By jeremy at 2018-05-25 16:53 |
| **Privacy Policy**  <br>  <br>LinuxQuestions.org does not sell members’ personal information.  <br>  <br>We collect the following personal information: email address, username, password, and IP address. We use this information to operate, maintain, and improve the site.  <br>  <br>We will only use this information for the purposes for which we collected or received it.  <br>  <br>**Advertising**  <br>  <br>This site displays 3rd party ads. We do not share any information with any 3rd party directly.  <br>  <br>**External Links**  <br>  <br>This site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.  <br>  <br>**Public Forums**  <br>  <br>This site makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  <br>  <br>**Security**  <br>  <br>This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.  <br>  <br>**Third Party Tools**  <br>  <br>We may use third party tools to improve the performance and features of our Website. These third party tools are designed to collect only non-personal information about your use of our Website. However, you understand that such tools are created and managed by parties outside our control. As such, we are not responsible for what information is actually captured by such third parties or how such third parties use and protect that information. |

All times are GMT -5. The time now is 11:44 PM.

**[Contact Us](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/sendmessage.php) - [Advertising Info](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/adinfo.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) - [Rules](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/rules.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) - [Privacy](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/privacy.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) - [LQ Merchandise](http://www.zazzle.com/linuxquestions*) - [Donations](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/donation.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) - [Contributing Member](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/member.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) - [LQ Sitemap](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/sitemap.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) -**

|     |
| --- |
| Main Menu |
| * [Linux Forum](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/)<br>* [Search](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/search.php)<br>* [LQ Tags](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/tags/)<br>* [Linux Tutorials](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/answers/?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b)<br>* [LQ Deals](https://deals.linuxquestions.org/)<br>* [Linux Wiki](http://wiki.linuxquestions.org/)<br>* [Download Linux](http://iso.linuxquestions.org/)<br>* [Social Groups](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/groups/)<br>* [LQ Blogs](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/blog/)<br><br>[(Con't)](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/privacy.html#main_cont?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b) |

Advertisement

Advertisement

|     |
| --- |
| My LQ |
| * [Login](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/lqlogin.php?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b)<br>* [Register](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/register.php)<br><br>[](https://www.linuxquestions.org/'https://rev.linuxquestions.org/www/delivery/ck.php?n=8cac360\%27) |

|     |
| --- |
| Write for LQ |
| LinuxQuestions.org is looking for people interested in writing Editorials, Articles, Reviews, and more. If you'd like to contribute content, [let us know](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/sendmessage.php). |

|     |
| --- |
| Main Menu |
| * [LQ Calendar](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/calendar.php)<br>* [LQ Rules](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/rules.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b)<br>* [LQ Sitemap](https://www.linuxquestions.org/linux/sitemap.html?s=8c527ed12be8383db445c9d41d79655b)<br>* [Site FAQ](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/faq.php)<br>* [View New Posts](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/search.php?do=getnew)<br>* [View Latest Posts](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/lqsearch.php?do=getnew&daysprune=7)<br>* [Zero Reply Threads](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/lqsearch.php?do=noreplies)<br>* [LQ Wiki Most Wanted](http://wiki.linuxquestions.org/wiki/Special:Wantedpages)<br>* [Jeremy's Blog](http://jeremy.linuxquestions.org/)<br>* [Report LQ Bug](https://www.linuxquestions.org/questions/project.php) |

|     |
| --- |
| Syndicate |
| [](http://www.linuxquestions.org/syndicate/lqlatest.xml)  Latest Threads  <br>[](http://www.linuxquestions.org/syndicate/lqnews.rss)  LQ News  <br><br>Twitter: [@linuxquestions](http://twitter.com/linuxquestions) |
